Welcome to this video where we
see in a few minutes
a French expression.
So today we're going to see
the expression "noyer le poisson".
This expression is a bit strange because
that drowning a fish,
in fact, it's impossible.
The fish breathes in the water.
So, let's see what this
expression of the contextualizations
and especially, where it comes from.
So when we say we're trying to drown
the fish,
it means we're trying to divert a
conversation in a conversation with
someone, there's a topic that's brought up.
And you, you don't want to talk
or do you try to talk about yourself?
Really try to divert
the conversation so that we don't
to stop talking about this subject.
Because it bothers you?
It embarrasses you
or are you not allowed to talk about it?
Because you promised someone that
you had not talked about this subject?
So you are really trying to
drown the fish.
So you're trying to bury the issue
and move on to another
theme in the conversation.
I'll give you some context.
It's okay, it will help you
to understand better.
Here is a first context.
So often,
you can say that politicians try to
to drown the fish when they don't have the
the answer to a question.
If you ask a politician how much
costs for a subway ticket in Paris,
he might answer the important one
it's not how much the ticket costs
but how much you can afford
reimburse every year
people who take the subway.
You see, there, he has perfectly
drown the fish.
In fact, he didn't know
to answer the question.
So he diverted the conversation.
He covered up, he has.
He hid a little that he didn't know how to
that he didn't know how to answer by changing the.
Changing the subject a bit,
here is another example.
If you have for example a friend
who is pregnant but doesn't want to say so yet
to say so yet and someone tells you
that you noticed, Maria has really
Maria has really put on weight, unless she's pregnant.
And you, you haven't made much progress.
You keep it a secret,
you don't want to talk about it.
So, you're going to try to drown out
the fish, to divert the conversation
to talk about somebody else instead,
for example to answer it?
Ah, I don't know, I didn't notice.
On the other hand, I don't know if you saw
Sandra, but she is in her
eighth month of pregnancy.
She's really huge.
It looks like it's going to explode.
You have.
Divert the conversation you will drown
the fish, this expression noyer le poisson
the fish, in fact, it becomes a date
of the time and it was used to say
that we put a lot of sauce
on the fish,
to actually hide the taste of a fish
that was not very fresh,
which calls for a fort.
It was not very good anymore
to put a lot of sauce on it
to hide the bad taste of the fish.
That's it for this expression.
That's it for today.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
If you liked it, don't forget
to give it a thumbs up.
Don't hesitate to tell me in comments
if there are any expressions
that you would like me to explain
and put in context.
I wish you all a very,
day and I hope to see you very, very
and see you very, very soon.